■
字幕来源：CMCT
后期：筆孞·Lee    Sung1219
Excuse me.
I beg your pardon. Aren't you Guy Haines?
Oh, sure.
I saw you blast Faraday right off the court in South Orange last season.
- Made the semifinals, didn't you? - Yeah.
Oh, I certainly admire people who do things.
By the way, my name is Bruno. Bruno Anthony. See?
It's corny, but my mother gave it to me...
- so I wear it to please her. - How do you do?
I don't talk much. You go ahead and read.
Thanks.
You know, it must be pretty exciting to be so important.
- Tennis player isn't so important. - But people who do things are.
Me, I never do anything.
I suppose you're going to Southampton for the doubles.
You are a tennis fan.
Gee, I wish I could go watch you, but I've gotta get back to Washington.
I'm from Arlington, you know.
- Cigarette? - No, thanks. I don't smoke much.
Me, I smoke too much.
Oh, here.
Oh, thanks.
Elegant.
"From A to G." I'll bet I can guess who "A" is.
- Yeah? - Anne Morton.
You see, sometimes I turn the sports page, and I see the society section.
And the pictures. She's very beautiful.
Senator Morton's daughter, huh?
You're quite a reader, Mr. Anthony.
Yes, I am. Ask me anything.
I got the answer.
Even about people I don't know.
Like who would like to marry whom...
when his wife gets her divorce.
Perhaps you read too much.
Oh, there I go again. Too friendly. It always happens.
I meet somebody who I like and admire, and I open my mouth too much.
That's all right, forget it. I guess I'm a little jittery.
Oh, there's a new cure for that.
- Waiter. - Yes, sir.
Scotch and plain water, please. A pair. Doubles.
The only kind of doubles I play.
You'll have to drink both.
And I can do it.
When's the wedding?
- What? - The wedding. You and Anne Morton.
It was in the papers.
It shouldn't have been. Unless they legalized bigamy overnight.
Oh, I've got a wonderful theory about that.
Someday I'll tell you about it.
But right now, I suppose divorce is, well, the simplest operation.
It's wonderful having you as company all the way to New York.
I'm not going direct. I'm stopping off at Metcalf.
Metcalf? Who would want to stop off at Metcalf?
Well, it's my hometown.
Oh, I get it. A little chat with your wife about the divorce.
Close enough.
Thanks. I think I will.
Well, here's luck.
Drink up, and we'll have lunch sent to my compartment.
Thanks, but I'll go to the dining car. Oh, waiter.
Are there any seats in the diner?
Not for about 20 minutes, sir.
You'll have to lunch with me.
here's to the next Mrs. Haines.
Sure, I went to college. Got kicked out of three of them.
Drinking and gambling.
Not like you, huh? All right, so I'm a bum.
Who said you were?
My father.
He hates me.
With all his money,
he thinks I ought to catch the 8:05 bus
every morning...
punch a time clock and work my way up selling paint or something.
What do you think of a man like that?
- Well, I think possibly... - Yes, I hate him too.
I tell you, I get so sore at him sometimes...
I want to kill him.
- I don't think you know what you want. - Well, I want to do something.
Everything.
You know, I've got a theory that you should do everything before you die.
Have you ever driven a car blindfolded at 150 miles an hour?
Not lately.
I did. I flew in a jet plane too.
Man, that's a thrill. Almost blew the sawdust out of my head.
And I'm going to make a reservation on the first rocket to the moon.
- What are you trying to prove? - Well, I'm not like you.
You're lucky. You're smart.
Marrying the boss' daughter makes
a nice shortcut to a career, doesn't it?
Marrying the senator's daughter has nothing to do with it.
Can't I look beyond a tennis net without being out for something?
Take it easy. I'm your friend,
remember? I like you.
I'd do anything for you.
Sure, Bruno.
We'll be pulling in soon. I've got to change trains.
What did you say her name was? Your wife's?
- Miriam. - Miriam, that's it.
Miriam Joyce Haines.
I suppose she played around a lot.
Skip it, Bruno.
It's painful for a man to discover he's been a chump.
Okay.
Wanna hear one of my ideas for a perfect murder?
The "light socket in the bathroom"...
or the "carbon monoxide in the garage"?
Neither one. I may be old-fashioned,
but murder is against the law.
What is a life or two, Guy?
Some people are better off dead.
Well, like your wife and my father, for instance.
Oh, that reminds me of a wonderful idea I had once.
I used to put myself to sleep at night figuring it out.
Now, let's say that you'd like to get rid of your wife.
- That's a morbid thought. - No, no, no. Just suppose.
Let's say you had a good reason.
- No, let's not... - No, no. Let's say.
You'd be afraid to kill her. You know why. You'd get caught.
And what would trip you up?
The motive.
Ah... Now, here's my idea.
I haven't got time to listen.
Listen. It's so simple too.
Two fellows meet accidentally, like you and me.
No connection. Never saw each other before.
Each one has somebody that he'd like to get rid of.
So. they swap murders.
Swap murders?
Each does the other's murder.
Then there's nothing to connect them.
Each one has murdered a stranger.
Like you do my murder, I do yours.
We're coming into my station.
For example, your wife, my father. Crisscross.
What?
We do talk the same language, don't we?
Sure, we talk the same language. Thanks for lunch.
I'm glad you enjoyed it. The lamb chops were a little overdone.
Nice meeting you.
Now, you think my theory's okay, Guy?
I mean, you like it?
Sure, Bruno, sure.
They're all okay.
Crisscross.
Hi, Bill.
Guy Haines! Good to see you, boy.
You better win at Southampton.
I got 2 bucks on you.
- Park these in a lucky spot, will you? - Sure thing.
One-fifty, 2, 3, 4, 5. There you are.
- Thank you very much. - You're welcome.
- Hello, Guy. - You're looking well, Miriam.
So are you.
Got a nice tan playing tennis with all your rich friends.
What time do we meet your lawyer?
- What's your hurry? - My hurry?
That's funny, coming from you.
You're the one who's in a hurry, aren't you?
When you wouldn't give me the divorce...
I sort of hoped it was
because you were jealous.
I got over being jealous a long time ago, Miriam.
Let's talk in here.
Well, this is cozier.
Sort of like old times, isn't it?
Oh, skip it, Miriam.
It's pretty late to start flirting with a discarded husband.
Especially when you're going to have another man's baby.
You know, I think you're handsomer than ever.
Let's see your lawyer and get this over with.
You bring the money? Lawyers are expensive.
Yes.
Here it is.
If I'd known what all that tennis nonsense of yours would lead to...
I wouldn't have run out on you.
What are you trying to say, Miriam?
I'm not getting a divorce.
You little double-crosser! I didn't want this divorce. You did.
You've been harping about it all year!
It's a woman's privilege to change her mind.
Now I can buy me some pretty new clothes.
I wouldn't want you to be ashamed of me in Washington...
when we go to all those swanky parties.
- What do you mean by that? - Don't look so mad, Guy.
You smile when your picture's taken for the newspaper.
Especially with Anne Morton on your arm.
Let's not talk about Anne Morton.
It's serious between you two, huh?
You can throw all your dreams about her into the ashcan.
- I'm coming to Washington. - What for?
To have my baby and be with you.
Why me? It's not my baby.
Yes, but people don't know that, Guy. Do they?
Make a pretty story, the senator's daughter involved with a married man.
- Especially when he's to be a father. - You conniving liar!
Keep your voice down.
What happened? He run out on you?
No man runs out on me. Not even you.
You've been trying to get rid of me long enough.
Now I'll go you one better. I never wanna see or hear you again.
I could be pathetic as the deserted mother in court. Think it over.
- Who would believe you? - I'm warning you.
That's what should happen to people like you. I'd like to find...
Break it up, folks. This isn't the place for a family quarrel.
I'm sorry.
I'm leaving.
You heard what I said, Guy Haines.
You can't throw me away! I'm coming to Washington to have my baby!
- Tell that to the Senate! - Please.
Anne?
Anne, darling, I...
Yes, I'm in Metcalf.
No, everything didn't go smoothly.
She doesn't want the divorce. Not now.
It's unbelievable.
Yes, I know how you must feel.
But you sound so savage, Guy.
Sure, I sound savage. I feel savage. I'd like to break her neck.
I said, I'd like to break her foul, useless little neck.
What's that?
I said, I could strangle her!
I do wish you'd keep your hands quiet.
You're so restless lately.
I like them to look just right.
Did I file them too short?
Oh, no, Ma. They're just fine. Thanks.
- What's the matter? - I'm all right. Don't worry about me.
But you look so pale, dear.
Are you out of vitamins?
I took a bottle yesterday, Ma.
A whole fifth.
Oh, but you have that look, dear. I always can tell.
Now, you haven't been doing anything foolish?
I do hope you've forgotten all about that silly little plan of yours.
- Which one? - About blowing up the White House.
Oh, Ma, I was only fooling.
Besides, what would the president say?
You're a naughty boy, Bruno.
You could always make me laugh.
Get shaved before your father gets home.
I'm sick and tired of bowing and scraping to the king.
Now, now. Now, let's not lose control.
Come see my painting.
Bruno, I do wish you'd take up painting.
Such a soothing pastime.
Oh, Mother, you're wonderful!
That's the old boy, all right. That's Father.
Is it?
I was trying to paint Saint Francis.
Excuse me, sir. They're ready with your call to Southampton.
I want to talk to you and your mother.
Sorry, Father. Long distance.
- Must you take that tone with Bruno? - Hello.
Guy. Bruno.
What? Now, who did you say this is?
Bruno, Guy. Bruno Anthony. Don't you remember? On the train.
Are you getting your divorce?
He should be sent someplace for treatment before it's too late!
Oh, so she double-crossed you.
Are you going to see her again?
Now, just let's have lunch first...
I'm going to have that boy taken care of.
If necessary, put under restraint!
- Good night, Mom. - Now, don't stay out late.
- There's the bus! - Hold on, driver!
- Hey, driver! - Hey!
- Hurry! - Hey, wait a minute!
Driver.
- I'll get it, Tom. Go ahead. - Okay.
- Watch your step. - Thanks.
Easy does it, Tommy.
- Hey, I'm hungry. - Oh, hungry already!
Hot dogs! Get them while they're hot! Red-hot! Right over here!
Yes, sir, get your popcorn here.
Fresh popcorn! Only 5 cents a bag!
Come and get it!
Come and get it! Here you are!
- Three cones, Arthur. - What flavors you got?
- Vanilla. - Vanilla? Swell.
- I should've had a hot dog before this. - A hot dog?
Satisfy my craving a little better.
Craving for what?
I never saw a girl eat so much.
- Where do you put it all? - This is good.
Want some money?
Are we going to the Tunnel of Love?
- The Tunnel of Love? Come on! - Yeah. Great. Come on.
- What do you call that? - I don't know.
You think we should get her weighed?
Stick them up. Bang, bang.
Come closer, come closer! Step right up and win a baby doll.
Let's go see who's the strongest.
Sixteen hundred. Who wants to take a chance to win a Kewpie Doll?
- Strongest pays for the merry-go-round. - Fair enough.
Here we go. Watch it.
Come on.
Sixteen hundred. How about you, sir?
Thank you.
Here we go!
Seventeen hundred. You did not win the Kewpie Doll that time.
Will you try it again, sir?
Here we go. Watch it now.
Sixteen hundred. Will you try it again
and win a nice Kewpie Doll for the lady?
Try your luck, mister?
Come closer, come closer!
Step right up and win a baby doll!
Hot dogs! Here you are, folks!
Get them while they're hot! Red-hot! Right over here!
Here we go.
You just won a Kewpie Doll.
Why, he's broken the thing.
Come on, Miriam. Come on.
Everybody, step right up and get your ticket cashed!
Let's go on the merry-go-round!
Let's sing. Come on.
Let's go for a boat ride.
Get your popcorn here! Fresh popcorn!
- How about some popcorn? - You don't want any more to eat.
Not now!
No fun necking with a mouthful of popcorn.
- Come on. - Okay.
Take a ride. Take a slide.
Take a trip with lots of zip. This way, ladies and gentlemen.
- How about this one? - I'm gonna drive.
You're gonna drive?
Don't rock the boat!
- Here we go. - Anchors aweigh, admiral.
You sure you know how to steer this tub?
- Make him stop! Make him stop! - I'm trying to steer the boat.
Hey, what's that? What are you doing?
Come on, come on, Miriam.
- Come on. - Stop it!
Hang on.
- Oh, wait a minute. - Easy does it, now. Let's not break a leg.
We got use for you later.
Hey, Miriam!
Is your name Miriam?
Why, yes. How did you...?
Hey, Miriam!
Miriam, where are you?
Miriam!
Miriam, come on. Stop fooling.
Think you can give us the slip?
- Hey, come on! Stop hiding. - Miriam, where are you?
Lost your girl, George? Miriam!
Hey, here she is.
Look, she's fainted.
Come on, Miriam, get up.
What's the matter?
- She's dead! - Dead?
Help, somebody, help!
Somebody send for a doctor!
Help!
Help! Help!
Help, somebody, help!
Help! Bring help! Somebody bring a doctor! Help!
Go get a cop. I don't know what's going on over there.
Thank you.
- What's your opinion? - You'll never make the Metropolitan.
Name's Collins.
On sabbatical, Delaware Tech. Glad to meet you.
I just made a speech in New York on integration.
In differential calculus, a function is given...
and the differential is obtained. You understand?
Yes, I understand.
You do?
Guy!
Guy.
Over here, Guy.
- Hello, Guy. - What are you doing here?
At this time of night?
You don't seem very pleased to see me.
- I've brought you a little present. - What do you mean?
What's this all about?
Recognize them?
It was very quick.
She wasn't hurt in any way.
It was all over in no time.
I knew you'd be surprised.
There's nothing for us to worry about. Nobody saw me.
Only Miriam.
And I was very careful, Guy.
Even when I dropped your cigarette lighter there, I went back to pick it up.
Are you trying to tell me...? Why, you maniac!
But, Guy, you wanted it.
We planned it on the train together, remember?
- Where are you going? - Where do you think I'm going?
- I'm gonna call the police, of course. - But you can't.
We'd both be arrested for murder.
We'd both be arrested for murder?
You're just as much in it as I am.
We planned it together. Crisscross.
You think you can get away with it?
Oh, come, now.
Why should I go to Metcalf to kill a total stranger?
Unless it was part of the plan, and you were in on it.
You're the one who benefits, Guy.
You're a free man now.
I didn't even know the girl.
I had nothing to do with this. The police will believe me.
Guy, if you go to the police now...
you'll just be turning yourself in as an accessory.
You see, you have the motive.
- What is it? - My telephone.
Someone has some news for you, Guy.
It's the police.
You've got me acting like I'm a criminal.
Why, you crazy fool!
Don't you call me that.
Oh. Oh, you must be tired, Guy. I know I am.
I've had a strenuous evening.
But now, about my father, I've got the plan of the house already made.
And I have an old Luger pistol I got in a pawnshop in San Francisco...
But, Guy... Guy, wait a minute!
We have to talk. We have to arrange things.
Go, before I give you what you gave Miriam.
You're not yourself, Guy. You're tired.
When you think things over, you'll see I'm right. Tomorrow, we...
I never saw you before! I never want to see you again!
But we have...
Yes? Yes, Anne.
I'm sorry, darling. I just got in.
Of course I'm all right, but you sound upset.
Is anything wrong?
All right. I'll come over right away.
Anne, darling, you're trembling.
Guy, I wonder if you know how much I love you.
Brazen woman, I'm the one to say that.
I wanted you to know before...
Father wants to see you.
Good evening, sir.
Hello, Babs.
- Something dreadful's happened. - Sit down, Barbara.
There seems to be no way of diplomatically breaking tragic news.
I'm sorry, Guy, to be the one to tell you.
It concerns your wife.
She's been murdered.
The police have been trying to find you.
You're to call headquarters in Metcalf.
Miriam murdered?
She was strangled.
It happened on an island, in an amusement park.
It was sort of a lovers' lane, I believe.
Evidently, a sordid atmosphere.
She went there with the boys that found her,
so they're not suspects.
But you will be.
We can't overlook that murder is at our doorstep...
but don't drag it in here.
Let's not fool ourselves.
Police will say Guy wanted her dead so he could marry Anne.
This sort of crime, they go after the husband.
Guy had every motive.
Motive?
Well, she's right.
Whichever way you look at it, I'm in a spot.
I'm sure you've got nothing to worry about.
If he hasn't an alibi for 9:30, he has plenty to worry about.
- You can tell them where you were. - Sherry.
Thank you.
Can't you, Guy?
Nine-thirty? I was on the train from New York to Washington.
There you are.
Who saw you? Did you speak to anyone? You'll need a witness.
Yes, I did speak to someone.
- Someone you know? - No.
His name was...
C... Col... Collins! He's a professor.
- Harvard? - Delaware Tech.
Then everything's all right.
Not quite. He'll still have to answer questions.
Routine. Pure routine.
There'll be many reporters here in the morning.
Daddy doesn't mind a little scandal. He's a senator.
It can't be helped, darling. It's not your fault.
No one can say you had anything to do with it.
Someone might say it. I'd do anything to keep you all out of this mess.
Be guided by my experience.
Never lose any sleep over accusations. Unless they can be proved, of course.
Dreadful business. Dreadful. Poor, unfortunate girl.
She was a tramp.
She was a human being.
Even the most unworthy of us has a right to life and the pursuit of happiness.
From what I hear, she pursued it in all directions.
Father, it's getting terribly late. Guy looks so tired.
Of course, of course. Back to bed, Barbara.
Nothing stands in your way. Now you can be married right away.
Think of it, you're free!
You don't always have to say what you think.
Father, I am not a politician.
Remember to call Captain Turley.
Yes, sir. Good night.
- Anne... - It'd be wonderful...
to have a man love you so much he'd kill for you.
I kept saying over and over I was being silly.
But there was one horrible moment tonight when the news came through.
I kept remembering what you shouted on the phone from Metcalf.
That I could...
Don't even say it.
Forget you ever said it.
Even more terrifying than the murder itself was...
the horrible thought that if you had done it...
we would have been separated. Perhaps forever.
I couldn't stand that.
I couldn't bear it.
Captain Turley is expecting me. Guy Haines.
Just a moment, Mr. Haines.
Would you come in, please?
Good of you to be so prompt, Mr. Haines.
- This is Lieutenant Campbell. - How do you do?
- Won't you sit down? - Thank you, sir.
I know you're busy,
so we won't detain you any longer than necessary.
You've already been good enough to tell us where you were last evening.
We've found the gentleman you spoke with on the train.
- I saw him outside. - Please come in, professor.
Professor Collins, this is Mr. Haines.
He was with you on the train last night.
I'm sorry, but I really don't remember meeting this gentleman.
Unfortunately, I remember very little of our trip from New York.
You see, we had a little celebration.
But we were sitting opposite each other...
in the observation car.
- You were singing a song about a goat. - A goat?
And calculus. You were going over a speech you made.
I was?
I'm very sorry, Mr. Haines.
I certainly must have been celebrating.
Captain, is it so important whether Professor Collins remembers me?
I've been able to name a man who was on the train with me.
You've found him.
Isn't that proof of where I was at 9:30 last night?
Thank you. Hello, dear. Senator. Babs.
- Hello, darling. Have you had dinner? - On the train.
You've been in Metcalf all this time? We expected you hours ago.
I didn't. They sometimes leave a suspect in the can all night.
Sit down, Guy. Sit down. Barbara, some coffee.
You had no trouble with the police...
once they verified your alibi?
When an alibi is full of bourbon, it can't stand up.
You mean the professor was boiled?
Completely.
He didn't remember me.
But you knew he was on the train. Isn't that proof you were on it too?
Apparently, not at the right time.
They suggested I could have caught the train at Baltimore...
after Miriam was murdered.
They had it all worked out in their timetable.
Well, that's ridiculous. They're acting as if you were guilty.
Everything will be all right.
The police were just being thorough.
Weren't they, Daddy?
I certainly hope so. What's your next move?
Whatever it is, the police will know about it.
Oh. Oh, they gave me a present.
Take a look.
My guardian angel.
You're being tailed.
That's Leslie Hennessy.
He works 16 hours a day.
Somebody else takes over for the next eight.
Actually, he's a very nice fellow.
I'll have him called off.
Obstructing the wheels ofjustice, Daddy?
I'm afraid where I go, Hennessy goes.
Even to the Senate.
- Is he likely to picket my office? - Very likely.
I would suggest, for your own peace of mind, of course...
that you work at the house. It'll be less embarrassing for you.
But what about practicing?
Perhaps I'd better forget about Forest Hills.
My dear boy...
wouldn't it look rather awkward if you suddenly canceled all your plans?
He's right. You mustn't do anything that looks suspicious.
- You must act as if nothing happened. - Escorted by Mr. Hennessy.
A call for you, Mr. Haines. They say it's urgent.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
- Hello? - Hello, Guy.
It must have been some mistake. It wasn't for me.
I suppose I was lucky being seeded fifth.
I've never seen the Forest Hills tournament. I look forward to it.
You mean we'll be going together, Hennessy?
Ah, don't worry. By that time, this thing will be all cleared up.
- You ever think of turning professional? - I don't have to do that.
After tennis, I'm going into politics.
- I hope. - Politics?
It's good I don't report that to the chief.
If he knew that,
he'd put 10 men on you. He says...
Let's take this cab. It's getting late.
- Pentagon building, please. - Oh, no, not there.
I always get lost.
We'd better be getting back.
We've actually been alone for an hour. Seems almost indecent.
You like?
I like.
I was beginning to feel like a goldfish.
Guy!
Excuse me.
Will you stop pestering me?
You're spoiling everything. You're making me come out into the open.
I've tried calling you on the phone.
Did you get my note?
Why haven't you called me?
My father is leaving for Florida next week.
Listen, you... There's a detective outside. He'll see us together.
Isn't that Anne Morton?
Slight improvement over Miriam, huh, Guy?
Stay away from me, I'm telling you.
Who is it, Guy?
I never saw him before. Just some tennis fan.
Here's a special delivery. It's marked "personal."
- Thank you. - You getting any practice today?
Yes, if I can get a court at the club.
- Barbara, who are you waving at? - Mr. Hennessy.
It's a shame Daddy won't let us have him in.
- You met him yet, Louise? - No.
He's awfully cute.
Okay, you ready, Guy?
Yeah.
Hi, darling. This is Mr. Anthony, a friend of Monsieur and Madame Darville.
Guy Haines.
I've been a fan for a long time, Mr. Haines.
I follow everything you do.
Mr. Anthony has been telling us some charming stories. Very funny.
I've been talking to your shadow.
Guy, did you know Mr. Hennessy helped crack
that ax murder?
The one with the body cut up and hidden in the butcher shop?
He was locked in the icebox with the left leg for six hours.
He pulls those things out of his hat.
Who's the interesting Frenchman with the Darvilles?
His name's Anthony.
He's not French.
- How are you? - Delightful to see you, Barbara.
How sweet you look.
I hope you won't forget our party on Thursday, madame.
- We're planning on it. - But of course.
This is my sister. Barbara, this is Mr. Anthony.
How do you do?
Is your name Miriam?
- Hi, Hennessy. - Hi.
- I won't keep you out late tonight. - Oh?
With Forest Hills tomorrow, I've got to sleep.
That's too bad.
Hammond will be on duty in a couple of hours.
I'd like to see him earn his salary.
Doesn't that bloodhound ever relax?
He sticks so close, he's beginning to grow on me.
Like a fungus.
He thinks you're a very suspicious character.
But then he doesn't trust anybody, not even himself.
Come on, Hennessy.
- Don't forget your sleeping bag. - Yeah.
If I wait too long on a sidewalk, my feet get cold.
- If I sit too long on those stone steps... - Don't worry.
Since you
told Barbara about that icebox, you're her favorite charity.
- She'll send a butler to defrost you. - Cute kid.
Good evening, Miss Morton.
- This is Mr. Anthony, Father. - Mr. Anthony.
How do you do, sir?
I'd like to talk with you sometime, sir...
and tell you about my idea for harnessing a life force.
It'll make atomic power look like the horse and buggy.
I'm already developing my faculty for seeing millions of miles.
And, senator,
can you imagine being able to smell a flower on the planet Mars?
I'd like to have lunch with you soon, sir...
tell you more about it.
- I'll see you later. - Goodbye.
I don't remember inviting him. Who is he?
A friend of the Darvilles.
Unusual personality.
- Excuse me, aren't you Judge Donahue? - That's right.
How do you do, sir? My name is Bruno Anthony.
What's he doing here?
I don't know.
After you've sentenced a man to the chair...
isn't it difficult to go out and eat your dinner after that?
When a murderer's caught, he's tried. When convicted, he's sentenced.
When he's sentenced to death, he must be executed.
- Quite impersonal, isn't it? - So it is.
Besides, it doesn't happen every day.
So few murderers are caught.
Mr. Anthony, you seem very interested in the subject of murder.
No more than anyone else.
- No more than you, for instance. - Me? Oh.
I'm not interested in murder.
Oh, come now. Everyone is interested in that.
Everyone has somebody that they want to put out of the way.
Surely, madam, hasn't there been a time...
that you didn't want to dispose of someone?
- Your husband, for instance? - Oh, good heavens, no!
Are you sure?
You mean there wasn't a tiny moment when you were made very angry?
What did you say?
Aha. There you are, you see? There you are.
Now...
you're going to do a murder.
How are you going to do it? That's the fascinating part.
How will you do it...? I didn't get your name.
Mrs. Cunningham.
Mrs. Cunningham, how are you going to do it?
Well, I suppose I'll have to get a gun from somewhere.
Oh, no, Mrs. Cunningham.
Bang, bang, bang, all over the place? Blood everywhere?
- How about a little poison? - Yes.
- Oh, that's better. That's better, Mrs... - Anderson.
That's better, Mrs. Anderson.
But, you see, Mrs. Cunningham is in a dreadful hurry.
Poison takes from 10 to 12 weeks...
if poor Mr. Cunningham is to die from natural causes.
You know, I read of a case once.
I think it would be a wonderful idea.
I can take him in the car and when we get to a very lonely spot...
hit him on the head with a hammer, pour gasoline over him and the car...
and set the whole thing ablaze.
And walk all the way home?
- No? - Oh, no. No, no.
I have the best way and the best tools.
Simple, silent and quick. The silent part being the most important.
Let me show you what I mean.
May I borrow your neck for a moment?
- Well, if it's not for long. - Oh.
When I nod my head, you try to cry out, and I'll bet you can't do it.
Just wait for the nod of my head.
Mr. Anthony! Help! Help! Somebody, come quick! Help!
Somebody, come. Quick, bring some water.
- Let's get him out of here. - Bring him into the study.
Will you help me take her upstairs, please?
- What happened? - He seemed to have fainted.
- What about her? - She was frightened.
They were playing a game of some sort.
I thought he was weird when he arrived. Who is he?
I hardly know him, sir.
Get him out of here as soon as you decently can.
It's a nice item for the gossips.
First thing you know, they'll be talking about orgies.
- I better get back. - Yes, sir.
What happened?
I was on a merry-go-round somewhere. It made me dizzy.
You mad, crazy maniac! You ought to be locked up.
Will you get out of here and let me alone?
But, Guy...
I like you.
You shouldn't have done that, Guy.
Come on, pull yourself together.
Here, let me.
Is your car here?
Driver's outside.
All right, come on.
What's the matter?
Did you see it happen?
He looked at me.
His hands were on her throat...
and he was strangling me.
How do you mean?
He was looking at her first...
then looked over at me.
He went into sort of a trance.
Oh, it was horrible.
He thought he was murdering me.
But why me, Anne? Why me?
What did I have to do with it?
Do you know where Guy is?
He went out with that man.
You didn't meet him for the first time the other day, did you?
- When you introduced us at the club? - Yes.
Did you see how he stared at Barbara?
No, I didn't particularly.
He stared at her the same way tonight...
while his hands were around Mrs. Cunningham's throat.
What did Miriam look like?
Why ask me? You've seen her picture.
Go on. I want you to tell me.
- She was dark, not too tall, rather pretty. - What else?
What else is there?
She wore glasses, didn't she, Guy?
Yes.
She looked something like Barbara, didn't she?
How did you get him to do it?
I get him to do it?
He killed Miriam, didn't he?
Tell me, didn't he?
Yes.
He's a maniac.
I met him on the train going to Metcalf.
He had a crazy scheme about exchanging murders.
I do his, he'd do mine.
What do you mean, your murder, Guy?
He read about me.
He knew about Miriam, about you.
He suggested if he got rid of Miriam for me,
I should kill his father.
You must've known he was talking nonsense.
But he wasn't. I didn't give it another thought.
And now a lunatic wants me to kill his father.
It's too fantastic.
Yes, isn't it?
You mean, you've known about Miriam all this time?
Since the first night. He gave me her glasses.
Why didn't you call the police?
And have them say what you did:
"Mr. Haines, how did you get him to do it?"
And Bruno would say we planned it together.
Oh, Guy, what are we gonna do?
I don't know, Anne. I don't know.
We'd better go inside. Your friend Hennessy is watching us.
You see, this is why I didn't want you to know anything about it.
I wanted to protect all of you. Barbara, your father.
Now that you know, you're acting guilty too.
If we could only talk to Father, to...
It's not good. I mustn't drag anyone else into this.
Come on, let's go.
You look worried.
Keep on your toes. Something funny's going on.
I've decided to do what you want.
I'll make that little visit to your father.
How about tonight?
Yes, I want to get this thing over with.
Does anyone know you've come home?
You'd better slip out again and stay out till after daylight.
Mr. Anthony.
Don't be alarmed, but I must talk to you about your son,
about Bruno.
Yes, Mr. Haines?
My father isn't home tonight, Mr. Haines.
I was about to tell you that on the phone.
But you made such a sudden decision.
I wondered why.
Since you sent me the key to your house, I decided to use it...
to make a little social call on your father.
I thought he'd be interested to know he has a lunatic son.
I assume that you have no intention of going ahead with our arrangement?
None whatsoever. I never had.
I see.
Well, then you'll have no further use for my key.
Nor this.
Look, Bruno. You're terribly sick.
I don't know much about these things,
but why don't you get some treatment?
Not only for your sake...
but you can't go on causing destruction...
to anyone you happen to meet.
I don't like to be double-crossed.
I have a murder on my conscience,
but it's not my murder.
It's yours.
And since you're the one to profit by it...
I think you should be the one to pay for it.
Well, I guess it's no use, Bruno.
We seem to have nothing further to discuss.
Don't worry. I'm not going to shoot you.
It might disturb Mother.
I'm a very clever fellow.
I'll think of something better than that. Much better.
He came back at 3:25. I didn't even know he was gone...
until his phone rang for half an hour.
Nobody sleeps that sound, so the janitor let me in.
- No Haines. - I wonder where he went.
- Probably hear of another dame murdered. - Shut up.
How about I contact Metcalf?
I think there's cause for more questioning.
Questioning? Let's take him in.
how many times must I tell you that we have nothing conclusive?
There's no evidence he was ever at the crime scene.
Can't you get that?
Now, just stay put till I get back.
Miss Morton, really.
I know Bruno's been in some very awkward scrapes...
but nothing so ridiculous as a murder.
Mrs. Anthony, you have to make him do something about this.
Don't you see that one word from him...
would get Guy out of this dreadful situation?
I'm sure that this whole thing is just some practical joke.
You know, Bruno, he sometimes goes a little too far.
I really shouldn't be saying this to an outsider...
but sometimes he's terribly irresponsible...
and gets into all kinds of escapades.
Don't you understand, Mrs. Anthony?
Your son is responsible for a woman's death.
Did Bruno tell you this?
Well, of course not, Mrs. Anthony.
Well, there you are.
Well, now, Miss Morton, it's very nice of you to call...
and if you'll excuse me, I must get back to my painting.
Do you care for painting, Miss Morton?
I find it very soothing.
Come see us again sometime.
I'm afraid that Mother wasn't very much help, was she?
She hasn't been well for a long time.
She's a little... How shall I say? Confused.
Poor Mother.
You know, I'm very upset with Guy.
He shouldn't have sent you on an errand like this.
Guy doesn't know I'm here, Mr. Anthony.
He's led you up the garden path, I'm afraid.
He must be very desperate to try to involve me.
I've been protecting him since that conversation on the train...
when he told me how much he hated his wife.
He tried to get me to go back to the island one night after dark...
to pick up his lighter so the police wouldn't find it?
He dropped it there, you know, when... Well, that night.
All the police are waiting for...
is one piece of evidence to convict Guy of the murder.
It's had me so worried.
But, of course, I couldn't do it.
It would be too risky.
And besides, it would make me an accessory.
Oh, Miss Morton. I understand how you feel.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have an urgent appointment.
I really must go now.
He said if the police found your lighter...
that's all they'd need to prove you were at the scene.
That lie about my wanting him to get
it back means he'll put it on that island.
I wanted to help, but I'm afraid all I did is make things worse.
Going there after you did only made him more furious.
No, darling. He said last night he'd think of something.
He certainly has.
Guy, you've got to get to Metcalf before he does.
You haven't time to play. You'd better tell them.
If they announce I won't play,
Hennessy's bound to be suspicious.
He'll keep me from getting near Metcalf.
- Well, then I'll go. - No, Anne.
Stay here and help me give Hennessy the slip after the match.
But that'll be too late.
Didn't Bruno say I wanted him to go there one night after dark?
- Yes. - That's what's in his mind now.
He won't expose himself in broad daylight.
If I can finish in three sets, I'll still...
You're on in a few minutes, Guy.
- Miss Morton. - Okay, Tim. I'll be right there.
This is what I think we'd better do.
If Turley said to, let's pick him up.
Let him have his game first.
First time I ever waited for a murder suspect...
to play tennis before I pulled him in.
The boys at headquarters hear about this, they'll send me...
- Good luck, Guy. - Thanks.
You got it straight.
Make sure Barbara has everything ready
as soon as the third set starts.
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention, please.
This men's singles match will be...
between Mr. Guy Haines and Mr. Fred Reynolds.
On the other hand, Guy Haines is a quiet, methodical player...
almost lackadaisical.
As a rule, he plays slowly between points, well within himself.
Linesmen ready?
Play.
15-love.
30-love.
30-15.
40-15.
Game, Mr. Haines. He leads, one game to love, first set.
Union Station.
Guy Haines is hitting harder, hurrying the play...
taking chances I've never seen him take.
This is a complete reversal of his usual watch-and-wait strategy.
40-30.
Oh, may I have a light, please?
Thanks.
Game, Mr. Haines. He leads, one game to love. Third set.
Guy Haines has caught the first two sets easily.
And if he keeps going, it'll be a straight-set win for him, sure.
Look, if he wins this next set, you'd better have everything ready.
Give the driver this $10.
I wish I understood what this is all about.
I'll tell you that later. Please hurry.
40-love.
Game, Mr. Reynolds.
Advantage, Mr. Reynolds.
Game, Mr. Reynolds. He leads.
I may have spoken too soon when I said...
this match looked to be about over.
Reynolds is up there knocking on the door.
Game, Mr. Reynolds.
Mr. Reynolds wins the third set.
Mr. Haines leading, two sets to one.
The set score is now 2-1. Guy Haines leading...
and we're 10-all in the fourth set.
This match, from a quick victory for Haines,
has turned into a dogfight.
30-all.
Down there. My cigarette case. It's very valuable.
- Down here? - Yes, get that grating up right away.
What's the trouble?
Can't we do something? I dropped my cigarette case.
It mightn't be any good.
Probably gone down the storm drain.
- Storm drain? - Maybe it lodged on the edge.
Don't they have a trap down there, like under a sink?
Don't just stand here, do something!
I guess we could phone the city engineer.
- Worst he could do is tell me to take... - No, look, mister.
- Relax, mister. - I don't want to relax.
Game, Mr. Haines.
Guy Haines is grim and determined.
He needs but one more game for the entire match.
40-30.
Just one point between Haines and the match!
Deuce.
Advantage, Mr. Haines.
You must think a lot of that, whatever it is.
Game, set and match, Mr. Haines.
Taxi's waiting at the entrance.
Isn't it wonderful? He won. It calls for a celebration.
- Oh, I'm so sorry. Let me. - It's quite all right.
No, please. Anne says you must have dinner with us tonight...
just the family and you and Guy.
I may be out of town.
But you'll be with Guy, surely?
- Hennessy! - I'm sorry. I wish I could.
Hennessy!
- You waiting for me? - Yes.
Penn Station.
Come on.
We need your help.
We're chasing a man.
Really? How exciting!
Where'd that man buy a ticket for?
- Metcalf. - Let's get him.
That's why we're not.
Let him go. This may lead to something big.
We'll phone Metcalf and let
them take over at that end.
What time does it get dark around here?
What's the hurry?
- What time does it get dark, I said? - Oh, soon enough.
- Excuse me. - It's quite all right.
- When do we get into Baltimore? - In about 30 minutes.
Late again, hmm?
Nice business he's doing since the murder.
People wanna see the scene of the crime.
Come on, come on. Come closer. Here we are.
It's not a very nice way to make money.
Well, heck. Boat-keepers gotta eat too.
Business fell off something terrible for a while.
The smoochers wouldn't go near the place.
I'm afraid I don't know what a smoocher is.
Okay. So I ain't educated.
Amusement park. Quick.
He's gone to the amusement park.
Car 61 F, reporting Guy Haines' arrival at railroad station.
Suspect bound for amusement park in taxi.
There he is now.
Pick up Johnny and follow him.
We'll go around the other way.
Keep your eyes open. If you see him, let us know.
Any more boats?
It'll be a few minutes' wait.
Hey, Bruno!
- Haines, hold it! - Bruno!
Haines, hold it!
Bruno! Give me that lighter!
- Now, stay back, please! - Coming through.
- He's on there, sir. - He's the one who killed her.
We know that.
- Get someone to stop this thing. - I can handle it.
Hey, be careful! Stop!
- Well, do you want to do it? - No, I guess he can make it all right.
My little boy!
- Are you all right, Haines? - I think so.
He says this isn't the man we want. It's the other one.
- The one he was fighting with. - What do you mean?
Not Haines?
- But you pointed him out. - No, I didn't, sir.
I've never seen this man before. I meant the other one.
- What's this all about, Haines? - He has my lighter.
He wanted to plant it on the island to pin the whole thing on me.
Let me talk to him. Let me show you. Where is he?
Over here. Take it easy, pal.
We can't move it. It's too heavy.
- He's in a bad way. - Can't you get it off him?
They've done everything they can till the crane comes.
Hello, Guy.
Who's this?
This is Mr. Turley, the chief of police.
Oh...
They got you at last, huh, Guy?
Bruno, can you talk a little?
Can you tell the chief you have my lighter?
I haven't got it.
It's on the island where you left it.
Bruno, don't keep it up, not at a time like this.
- You know that... - I'm sorry, Guy.
I want to help you, but I don't know what I can do.
Captain Turley, can't I go through his pockets?
Of course not. Besides, he says he hasn't got it.
I think he's going.
He's finished.
Is this it?
Well, you were right.
Better keep this for the time being.
We'll clear this up in the morning.
How about staying overnight?
I imagine there's a lot you want to tell me. Nine o'clock all right?
Okay, Captain Turley. Thanks.
- Tell me where there's a telephone. - Up near the entrance.
Who was he, bud?
Bruno.
Bruno Anthony. Very clever fellow.
Hello?
Yes, operator, yes.
Guy?
Yes, darling, yes. Well, of course I'll be there.
Goodbye.
Guy will be back tomorrow. He wants me to bring him some...
I beg your pardon. But aren't you Guy Haines?